## Jd Beecham

Self-starter and have been working unsupervised across multiple states. Worked with multiple platforms and languages over the years. Worked as a tester, which gave insight of where problems can occur. Enjoys building iOS apps that interacts with a backend Node.js server.

#### Skills

- Front-End (HTML, React, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery)
- Back-End (Node.js, Express.js, PHP, REST)
- Troubleshooting Complex Equipment/Systems
- Xcode, Swift, SwiftUI, CocoaPods, UIKit, CoreML
- Git Version Control

- Databases and Data Structures (MongoDB, MySQL, and JSON)
- Ability to Self-educate on New Technology
- Networking
- Software Testing and Development
- C/C++

### **Education**

**GRADUATED 2008** 

# Bachelor of Science, Game and Simulation Programming / DeVry University

Focused on software engineering, software life cycles, multiple programming languages, artificial intelligence methods, networking, databases and data structures. Helped fellow students troubleshoot their programs and homework assignments. Also studied electrical engineering where we worked on circuits, processors, memory and low-level assembly language.

ATTENDED 2000 - 2002

## **Studied Computer Science / College of the Desert**

Worked on general courses and began my computer science studies. Learned multiple languages including C, Visual Basic, Assembly, PHP, HTML/CSS. Also studied networking, servers and databases using MySQL. Took courses on graphic design and learned Adobe applications like Photoshop and Illustrator.

## **Certificates**

**COMPLETED 2021** 

## The Complete 2021 Web Development Bootcamp / The App Brewery

Received my certificate of completion for an online training bootcamp on web development and web applications. Worked over 55 hours on 440 modules about front-end and back-end development. Built a variety of different websites using most of the popular technologies. Worked on front-end development with HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, Javascript ES6, DOM Manipulation, JQuery and React.JS. For back-end development, I worked on Bash Command Line, Node.JS, Express.JS, EJS, REST, APIs, Databases (MySQL and MongoDB), Mongoose, Authentication and Firebase.

**COMPLETED 2020** 

#### Complete iOS App Development Bootcamp / The App Brewery

Received my certificate of completion for an online training bootcamp on developing iOS applications. The course is 573 modules with over 60 hours of content to complete, not including the assignments. Covered many different subjects, including swift coding, SwiftUI, Core Data, networking, JSON, Google's Firebase Cloud, Machine Learning, and Augmented Reality.

## **Experience**

FEB 2019 - JUL 2020

#### Field Service Technician / Walman Instruments

Responsible for providing maintenance, troubleshooting and repairs to eye doctors and surgeons in Washington, Oregon, Idaho and Montana. Entrusted with a company vehicle and credit card. Maintain monthly travel and expense reports. Helped customers budget repairs and plan out maintenance services to keep costs low. Also, would plan multiple customers in the same area to reduce expenses. Wrote detailed repair tickets so customers would understand why certain equipment failed, where issues were, and break downs of where their costs all came from. If expected repair expenses exceeded the price of a new or used machine, I would explore options with the customer, and get them in contact with our sales manager for their region.

SEP 2001 - FEB 2019

#### Certified Lead Lab Technician / LensCrafters

Responsible for crafting prescription lenses to fit in a frame. Troubleshooted and repaired all the equipment in the lab and doctor's office. Repaired new equipment designs that didn't even have documentation yet. Developed excellent time management skills with the ability to meet deadlines. Trained in Lean Six Sigma to make sure lab is lean compliant and optimized. I was responsible for the lab's budget and ordering all the supplies. Wrote schedules and manage other technicians. I trained new employees and lab managers for multiple locations. Entrusted by the regional manager to travel to labs in the region to install, troubleshoot and train techs on operating and maintenance of new equipment. My lab was consistently ranked within the top 10 in the company out of over 1000 labs, which is based off of quality of work and workload.

OCT 2008 - OCT 2009

#### **Software Tester / Foundation 9 Entertainment**

Analyzed a range of different software titles on a variety of different systems including PC, Xbox, Sony PSP, PlayStation, Nintendo DS, and Wii. Worked on a prototype breadboard for a children's doll that interacted with a computer game. Along with testing titles, had to write technical documents including test cases, bug reports, and design suggestions. All documents had to be well written, clear but detailed to allow others to be able to reproduce and understandable without questions. Had the opportunity to work on several different databases and backend systems because we had to adapt to customer's owned systems. Received commendation from a senior programmer because of how helpful and knowledgeable I was for him during a Dora Explorer project.